JOÃO PEREIRA 🗯







+351 916 851 369



joao.pereira.dev@gmail.com

Motivated Programmer experienced Game in Development and Web Development: with Undergraduate Degree in Games and Multimedia complemented by independent learning.

Specializes in Gameplay Programming but has also some knowledge in Tools Programming in Unity. Previous experience on building simple 2D Engines and microgames in C++.

Curious and always looking forward to learning new quickly understanding new technologies. Organized and dependable, successful at managing priorities and meeting objectives. Always willing to help others to maintain and achieve team objectives.

After finishing college, promptly started exploring the market working as a freelancer, while solidifying knowledge in Game Development and learning JavaScript for Web Development.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- o C++
- C++ applied to Unreal
- C# applied to Unity
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and SQL Basics

GAME ENGINES

- Unity
- Unreal Engine

SOFT SKILLS

- Flexible and Adaptable
- Analytical and Critical Thinker
- Problem-Solver

LANGUAGES

PORTUGUESE

ENGLISH

C2 (Native)

C2 (Proficient)

WORK HISTORY

09.2021 - CURRENT

FREELANCER

Leiria (Remote)

- Developed and updated tracking spreadsheets using Trello and Notion.
- Developed modular gameplay solutions for Game Developers to add to their project with ease.
- Created some very simple tools to help boost level building productivity in Unity Updated and maintained Web Pages in Wordpress.

GAME PROGRAMMER

Codeming - Leiria

- Worked on creating and implementing gameplay logic to bring our ideas to life.
- Prepared weekly reports on changes, updates and progress of current projects.
- Updated documentation with project deviations to capture changes.
- Wrote solid, modular code for the various game systems, making it easier to implement any changes down the line while only affecting the intended systems.
- Built Characters and Levels according to the Game Designer's specifications and made sure they were playable and enjoyable.

11.2020 - 05.2021

SALES ASSOCIATE

2Smok - Leiria

- Organized racks and shelves to maintain store visual appeal, engage customers and promote specific merchandise.
- Provided positive first impressions to welcome existing, new and potential customers.
- Helped customers locate products and checked store system for merchandise at other sites.
- Answered customer questions regarding usage, desired usage, accessories and proper care for merchandise.
- Processed product returns and assisted customers with other selections.
- Trained and developed new hires in company processes, product knowledge, customer service and selling techniques.
- Tracked stock using company inventory management software

07.2017 - 09.2017

CASHIER

Minipreço - Almeirim

- Operated cash register for cash, check and credit card transactions.
- Helped customers complete purchases, locate items and join reward programs.
- Restocked and organized merchandise in front lanes

EDUCATION 09.2021

GAMES AND MULTIMEDIA (UNDERGRADUATE)

Polytechnic of Leiria